Hello and welcome to the fifth tutorial
on how to program in Gscript 2. Now in
this tutorial I'm going to show you more
about client side and server side and
how it affects the players and just the
play and just the player who's playing.
Now there's an NPC here. Actually no.
Yeah, there is an NPC here. You just
can't see it because there's no image
for it. This screen with the RC is mine.
That's me. This is the second
account. So now I'm going to edit this.
I took out some of the script. Now I'm
going to change on created to
onplayer chats. On player chats makes it
so as soon as the player says something,
it can be anything. The NPC will also
say something. Let's have the NPC say
this.
Hello
semicolon. Now I save
it. Oh, and remember this is under
client side. I'll show you the
difference of what happens if I take it
out in a second. So I upload. Now I
say hello MPC. It'll say hello. Now, as
you can
see, my the second account, the one
that's not, you know, with the the one
that's not an admin, does not see the
NPC saying hello. The reason is because
this is under client side. Everything
under client side only happens to the
player, not anyone else in the in the
level. Also, you can write script above
the client side if you want to. It it's
not just an entire script can be client
side and server side, not just the one
or the other. Anyway, if I change take
out the client
side, press
save. Now, I'm going to
say hi. The NPC will say hi and both
players will see it because it's it's on
server side, not client side.
Now, um I think that's about it for
client side. And oh yeah, I was going to
show one more thing. Let's
say I make it say
this.
Player.
Okay. Now, when we close it and save it
and upload
it, I'm going to say hello. The NPC says
hello. When I
say fun, the NPC says fun and both
players see
it. This is because I'm making the NPC's
chat equal to the player's
chat. If I put this in
quotes, watch what
happens. I'll say hi. It'll say player.
This is because it's thinking it as if
it wants me to say player. If I take out
the quotes, it knows that I'm trying to
make it say the players chat. You get
it? Well, I'm going to be going over all
this later in when I get to variables.
Anyway, that's it for this tutorial and
I'll see you